A. Jordan Nafa

DATA SCIENTIST AND BAYESIAN STATISTICIAN

Phone: 817-807-0035 | Email: adamjnafa@gmail.com | Github: ajnafa

Core Competencies

- Bayesian Statistics
- Causal Inference
- Decision Science
- Experimental Design
- Teaching
- Data Visualization
- Written & Verbal Communication
- Programming

About Me

Data Scientist with six years' experience working independently and in collaboration with colleagues to model complex data structures and provide insights necessary to answer business questions. Expertise in applying Bayesian inference, causal modeling, and decision science to inform business decisions and communicate uncertainty to stakeholders. Experience designing and building Bayesian analysis pipelines for optimization, promotional pricing, and personalized targeting in production settings. Explaining and distilling complex statistical concepts to colleagues, stakeholders, and executives.

Professional Experience

Game Data Pros, Inc. | Data Scientist

February 2023 - Present

- Developed and implemented robust production systems for Bayesian A/B testing of promotional campaigns and targeted offers in mobile and console games using Stan and Python.
- Designed and built a process for detailed end-to-end Bayesian analysis and automated reporting of experimental results using Python, R, and Quarto.
- Building and maintaining a production platform for Bayesian inference and the automatic detection of heterogeneous treatment effects in experiments with millions of users allowing the business to identify areas for personalization and optimize revenue.
- Designed and supervised the implementation of a system for Bayesian sequential optimization via multi-arm bandits.
- Managing and coordinating the timely execution of large data science and data engineering projects

University of North Texas | Teaching Fellow

October 2021 - March 2023

- Taught multiple undergraduate courses as instructor of record in the Department of Political Science.
- Designed and built undergraduate courses in Bayesian causal inference for social science research and American political behavior.
- Making extensive use of data visualization tools in R and Python to distill and communicate complex topics to non-technical audiences.
- Mentoring students and advising colleagues on statistical analysis and scientific programming.

University of North Texas | Research Scientist

August 2018 – October 2021

 Implemented efficiency tuning for Bayesian models to deliver increases in computational performance gains of up to 700%

- Wrote an R script to fully automate cross-platform data entry and reduce five hours of work per week to less than ten minutes.
- Directing, writing, and analyzing quantitative studies using data from a variety of sources.
- Collaborating on a variety of scientific research projects focused on the development and application of Bayesian inference in the social sciences.
- Consulting on aspects of research design, statistical analysis, data cleaning, scientific programming, and reproducibility.

Education

University of North Texas, Master of Arts in Political Science

December 2024

 Passed qualifying exams with distinction in February, 2021 and entered Doctoral candidacy (ABD) in August 2021. Left PhD program with a Masters in December 2024.

Texas Woman's University, Bachelor of Science in Government

August 2018

• Minor in computer science

Skills and Proficiencies

Stan

HTML/CSS

Git

Python

LaTeX

Quarto

Docker

R

SQL